Hey, everyone.
Thanks for coming to
our CS25 lecture today.
So today we're honored to
have Jim Fan from NVIDIA,
who we're talking
about generalist
agents in open-ended worlds.
And he's a senior AI
research scientist
at NVIDIA, where his mission is
to build generally capable AI
agents with applications to
gaming robotics and software
automation.
And his research spans
foundation models,
multimodal AI,
reinforcement learning,
and open-ended learning.
He obtained his PhD
degree in computer science
from here, at Stanford, advised
by Professor Fei-Fei Li.
And previously, he did
research internships
at OpenAI, Google AI, as well
as Mila-Quebec AI Institute.
So yeah, give it up for Jim.
Yeah, thanks for having me.
So I want to start with
a story of two kittens.
It's a story that gave me a lot
of inspiration over my career.
So I want to share
this one first.
You know, back in 1963,
there are two scientists
from MIT, Held and Hein.
They did this
ingenious experiment
where they put two newborn
kittens in this device,
and the kittens have not
seen the visual world yet.
So it's kind of like
a merry-go-round
where the two kittens are linked
by a rigid mechanical bar.
So their movements are,
like, exactly mirrored.
And there is an active kitten
on the right-hand side,
and that's the only one able to
move freely and then transmit
the motion over this link
to the passive kitten,
which is confined to the basket
and cannot really control its
own movements.
And then, after
a couple of days,
Held and Hein kind of
take the kidneys out
of this merry-go-round and then
did visual testing on them,
and they found that
only the active kitten
was able to develop a
healthy visual motor loop.
Like, you know,
responding correctly
to approaching objects
or, like, visual cliffs.
But the passive kitten did not
have a healthy visual system.
So I find this
experiment fascinating
because it shows the
importance of having
this embodied, active
experience to really go
round a system of intelligence.
And let's put this experiment
in today's AI context, right?
We actually have a very
powerful passive kitten,
and that is ChatGPT.
It passively observes
and rehearses
the text on the internet, and
it doesn't have any embodiment.
And because of
this, its knowledge
is kind of abstract
and ungrounded,
and that partially
contributes to the fact
that ChatGPT
hallucinates things that
are just incompatible
with our common sense
and our physical experience.
And I believe the future
belongs to active kittens, which
translates to generalist agents.
They are the decision-makers
in a constant feedback loop,
and they are embodied in
this fully immersive world.
They are also not
mutually exclusive
with the passive kitten.
And in fact, I see the
active embodiment part
as a layer on top of the
passive pre-training from lots
and lots of internet data.
So, are we there yet?
Have we achieved generalization?
You know, back in
2016, I remember
it was like spring of 2016.
I was sitting an undergraduate
class at Columbia University,
but I wasn't paying
attention to the lecture.
I was watching a board game
tournament on my laptop.
And this screenshot
was the moment
when AlphaGo versus Lee
Sedol-- and AlphaGo won
three matches out of five
and became the first ever
to beat a human champion
at a game of Go.
You know, I remember the
adrenaline that day, right?
I've seen history unfold.
Oh, my god.
We are, you know,
finally getting to HAI.
And everyone is like so excited.
And I think that was the
moment when AI agents entered
the mainstream.
But, you know, like when
the excitement fades,
I felt that even though our
goal was so mighty and so great,
it could only do one
thing and one thing alone.
Right?
And afterwards,
you know, in 2019,
there were more
impressive achievements.
Like OpenAI Five beating
the human champions
at a game of DOTA and AlphaStar
from DeepMind beat StarCraft.
But all of these,
with AlphaGo, they all
have a single kind of theme, and
that is to beat the opponent.
There is this one objective
that the agent needs to do,
and the model is trained on DOTA
or Go cannot generalize to any
other tasks.
It cannot even play other games,
like Super Mario or Minecraft,
and the world is fixed and have
very little room for open-ended
creativity and exploration.
So I argue that a
generalist agent
should have the following
essential properties.
First, it should
be able to pursue
very complex, semantically
rich, and open-ended objectives.
Basically, you explain what
you want in natural language,
and the agent should
perform the actions for you
in a dynamic world.
And second, the agent
should have a large amount
of pre-trained knowledge
instead of knowing
only a few concepts that's
extremely specific to the task.
And third, massively multitask.
Right?
A generalist agent,
as the name implies,
needs to do more than
just a couple of things.
It should be, in the best
case, infinitely multitask,
as expressive as human
language can dictate.
So what does it take?
Correspondingly, we need
three main ingredients.
First is the environment.
Right?
The environment needs
to be open-ended enough
because the agent's
capability is upper bounded
by the environment complexity.
And I'd argue that Earth is
actually a perfect example
because it's so open-ended
in this world we live in
that it allows an
algorithm called
natural evolution to produce all
the diverse forms and behaviors
of life on this planet.
So can we have a simulator that
is essentially a low-fi Earth,
but we can still run
it on the lab clusters?
And second, we need
to provide the agent
with massive pre-training
data because exploration
in an open-ended world from
scratch is just intractable,
and the data will serve
at least two purposes.
One, as a reference manual
on how to do things.
And second, as a
guidance on what
are the interesting
things worth pursuing.
And, you know, GPT is
only at least up to GPT 4.
It only learns from
pure text on the web.
But can we provide agent
with much richer data,
such as video walkthrough, or
like multimedia wiki documents,
and other media forms?
And finally, once we have the
environment and the database,
we are ready to train foundation
models for the agents,
and it should be flexible enough
to pursue the open-ended tasks
without any
task-specific assumptions
and also scalable
enough to compress
all of the multimodal data
that I just described.
And here, language,
I argue, will
play at least two key roles.
One is as a simple and
intuitive interface
to communicate a task, to
communicate the human intentions
to the agent.
And second, as a
bridge to ground
all of the multimodal
concepts and signals.
And that train of
thought landed us
in Minecraft, the best-selling
video game of all time.
And for those who
are unfamiliar,
Minecraft is a procedurally
generated 3D voxel world.
And in the game,
you can basically
do whatever your heart desires.
And what's so special
about the game
is that unlike AlphaGo,
StarCraft, or DOTA,
Minecraft defines no particular
objective to maximize,
no particular opponent
to beat, and doesn't even
have a fixed storyline.
And that makes it very well
suited as a truly open-ended AI
playground.
And here, we see people doing
extremely impressive things
in Minecraft.
Like, this is a
YouTube video where
a gamer built the entire
Hogwarts Castle block by block
by hand in a game.
And here's another example
of someone just digging
a big hole in the
ground and then
making this beautiful
underground temple with a river
nearby.
It's all crafted by hand.
And one more.
This is someone building
a functioning CPU circuit
inside a game because
there is something called
redstone in Minecraft that
you can build circuits out
of it, like logical gates.
And actually the game
is turing complete.
You can simulate a
computer inside a game.
Just think about
how crazy that is.
And here I want to
highlight a number, that
is 140 million active players.
And just to put this
number in perspective,
this is more than twice
the population of UK.
And that is the amount
of people playing
Minecraft on a daily basis.
And, you know, it
just so happens
that gamers are generally
happier than PhDs.
So they love to stream and
share what they're doing,
and that produces a huge amount
of data every day online.
And there's this treasure
trove of learning materials
that we can tap into for
training generalist agents.
You know, remember, the data is
the key for foundation models.
So we introduce MineDojo,
a new open framework
to help the community develop
generally capable agents using
Minecraft as a kind
of primordial soup.
MineDojo features
three major parts--
an open-ended environment, an
internet-scale knowledge base,
and then a generalist agent
developed with a simulator
and a massive data.
So let's zoom in the first one.
Here is a sample gallery
of the interesting things
that you can do
with MineDojo's API.
We feature a massive
benchmarking suite of more than
3,000 tasks, and this is by far
the largest open source agent
benchmark to our knowledge.
And we implement a
very versatile API
that unlocks the full
potential of the game.
Like, for example, MineDojo
supports multimodal observation
and for action
space, like moving,
or attack, or
inventory management.
And then it can be
customized at every detail.
Like you can tweak the terrains,
the weather, block placement,
monster spawning,
and just anything
you want to customize
in the game.
And given the simulator,
we introduce around 1,500
programmatic tasks, which are
tasks that have grown through
success conditions
defined in Python code.
And you can also
explicitly write down
like the sparse or the dense
reward functions using this API.
And some examples are like
harvesting different resources,
unlocking the tech tree, or
fighting various monsters
and getting reward.
And all these tasks
come with language
prompts that are templated.
Next, we also introduce
1,500 creative tasks that are
free-form and open-ended,
and that is in contrast
to the programmatic
tasks I just mentioned.
So, for example, let's say we
want the agent to put a house.
But what makes a
house a house, right?
It is ill-defined.
And just like image
generation, you
don't know if it generates
a cat correctly or not.
So it's very difficult to
use simple Python programs
to give these kind of
task reward functions.
And the best way is to use
foundation models trained
on internet-scale knowledge
so that the model itself
understands abstract
concepts like, you know,
the concept of a house.
And finally, there's
one task that
holds a very special
status called playthrough,
which is to beat the final boss
of Minecraft, the Ender Dragon.
So Minecraft doesn't
force you to do this task.
As we said, it doesn't
have a fixed storyline,
but it's still considered
a really big milestone
for any kind of
beginner human players.
I want to highlight it is an
extremely difficult task that
requires very complex
preparation, exploration,
and also martial skills.
And for an average
human, it will
take many hours or
even days to solve
easily over like
one million action
steps in a single episode.
And that would be the longest
benchmarking task for policy
learning ever created here.
So I admit I am personally
a below-average human.
I was never able to
beat Ender Dragon,
and my friends laugh at me.
And I'm like, OK, one day, my
AI will avenge my poor skills.
Right?
That was one of the
motivations for this project.
Now, let's move on to
the second ingredient,
the internet-scale knowledge
base part of MineDojo.
We offer three data sets here,
the YouTube, Wiki, and Reddit.
And combined, they are the
largest open-ended agent
behavior database ever
compiled to our knowledge.
The first is YouTube,
and we already
said Minecraft is one of the
most streamed games on YouTube.
And gamers love to narrate
what they're doing.
So we collected more than
700,000 videos with two billion
words in the
corresponding transcripts.
And these transcripts
will help the agent
learn about human strategies and
creativities without us manually
labeling things.
And second, the
Minecraft player base
is so crazy that
they have compiled
a huge Minecraft-specific
Wikipedia that basically
explains everything
you ever need to know
in every version of the game.
It's crazy.
And we scrape 7,000 wiki pages
with interleaving multimodal
data like images,
tables, and diagrams,
and here are some screenshots.
Like this is a gallery
of all of the monsters
and their corresponding
behaviors,
like spawn and attack patterns.
And also, like the
thousands of crafting
recipes are all present on the
Wiki, and we scrape all of them.
And while like complex
diagrams, and tables,
and embedded figures, now we
have something like GPT-4V.
It may be able to understand
many of these diagrams.
And finally, the
Minecraft subreddit
is one of the most active
forums across the entire Reddit.
And players showcase
their creations
and also ask questions for help.
So we scraped more than 300,000
posts from the Minecraft Reddit.
And here are some
examples of how
people use the Reddit as a kind
of Stack Overflow for Minecraft.
And we can see that some
of the top-voted answers
are actually quite good.
Like someone is asking, oh,
why doesn't my wheat farm grow?
And the answer says
you need to light up
the room with more torches.
You don't have enough lighting.
Now, given the massive task
suite and internet data,
we have the essential components
to build generalist agents.
So in the first
MineDojo paper, we
introduced a foundation
model called MineCLIP.
And the idea is very simple.
I can explain it
in three slides.
Basically, for our
YouTube database,
we have time-aligned
videos and transcripts.
And these are actually
the real tutorial videos
from our data set.
You see on the third
clip, you know,
as I raise my ax in
front of this pig,
there's only one thing that
you know going to happen.
There is actually
someone who said this,
a big YouTuber of Minecraft.
And then, given
this data, we train
MineCLIP in the same
spirit as OpenAI CLIP.
So for those who are
unfamiliar, OpenAI CLIP
is a contrastive model
that learns the association
between image and its caption.
And here it's a
very similar idea.
But this time it is a video
text contrastive model,
and we associate the text
with a video snippet that runs
about 8 to 16 seconds each.
And intuitively, MineCLIP
learns the association
between the video
and the transcript
that describes the
activity in the video.
And MineCLIP outputs a
score between 0 and 1,
where one means a perfect
correlation between the text
and video, and 0 means the text
is irrelevant to the activity.
So you see, this is effectively
a language-prompted foundation
reward model that knows
the nuances of things
like forests, animal, behaviors,
and architectures in Minecraft.
So how do we use
MineCLIP in action?
Here's an example of our agent
interacting with the simulator.
And here, the task is
shear sheep to obtain wool.
And as the agent explores
in the simulator,
it generates a video snippet
as a moving window, which
can be encoded and
fed into MineCLIP
along with an encoding
of the text prompt here.
And MineCLIP completes
the association.
Right?
The higher the
association is, the more
the agent's behavior
in this video aligns
with the language, which is
a task you want it to do.
And that becomes
the reward function
to any reinforcement
learning algorithm.
So this looks very
familiar, right?
Because It's essentially
RL from human feedback,
or RLHF in Minecraft.
And RLHF was the
cornerstone algorithm
that made ChatGPT
possible, and I
believe it will play a critical
role in generalist agents
as well.
I'll quickly gloss over
some quantitative results.
I promise there won't be like
many tables of numbers here.
For these eight tasks, we show
the percentage success rate
over 200 test episodes.
And here in the green
circle is two variants
of our MineCLIP method.
And in the orange circles
are the baselines.
So I'll highlight
one baseline, which
is that we construct a dense
reward function manually
for each task using
the MineDojo API.
It's a Python API.
And you can consider this
column as a kind of Oracle,
the upper bound of
the performance,
because we put a
lot of human efforts
into designing these reward
functions just for the tasks.
And we can see that
MineCLIP is able to match
the quality of many of these.
Not all of them, but
many of these manual
engineering rewards.
It is important to
highlight that MineCLIP
is open vocabulary.
So we use a single model for
all of these tasks instead
of one model for each, and we
simply prompt the reward model
with different tasks.
And that's the only variation.
One major feature
of foundation model
is strong generalization
out of box.
So can now agent generalize
to dramatic changes
in the visual appearance?
So we did this experiment
where, during training, we only
train our agents on a default
terrain at noon on a sunny day.
But we tested zero-shot in
a diverse range of terrains,
weathers, and day-night cycles,
and you can customize everything
in MineDojo.
And in our paper,
we have numbers
showing that MineCLIP
significantly
beats an off-the-shelf
visual encoder when
facing these kind of
distribution shift out of box.
And this is no surprise, right?
Because MineCLIP was trained
on hundreds of thousands
of clips from Minecraft
videos on YouTube,
which have a very good
coverage of all the scenarios.
And I think that is just a
testament to the big advantage
of using internet-scale data
because you get robustness out
of box.
And here are some demos of
our learned agent behaviors
on various tasks.
So you may notice that these
tasks are relatively short,
around like 100
to 500 timestamps.
And that is because
MineCLIP is not
able to plan over very
long time horizons.
And it is an inherent limitation
in the training pipeline
because we could only use 8
to 16 seconds of the video,
so it's constrained
to like short actions.
But our hope is to build an
agent that can explore and make
new discoveries autonomously
just all by itself,
and it keeps going.
And in 2022, this goal seems
quite out of reach for us.
MineDojo was June 2022.
And this year,
something happened.
And that is GPT-4, a language
model that's so good at coding
and long-horizon planning, so
we just cannot sit still, right?
We built Voyager, the
first large language
model-powered lifelong
learning agent.
And when we set Voyager
loose in Minecraft,
we see that it just keeps going.
And by the way, all
these video snippets
are from a single
episode of Voyager.
It's not from
different episodes.
It's a single one.
And we see that Voyager is
just able to keep exploring
the terrains, mine all kinds of
materials, fight monsters, craft
hundreds of recipes, and
unlock an ever-expanding tree
of diverse skills.
So how do we do this?
If we want to use the
full power of GPT-4,
a central question is
how to stringify things,
converting this 3D world into
a textual representation.
We need a magic box here.
And thankfully, again, the crazy
Minecraft community already
built one for us, and it's
been around for many years.
It's called Mineflayer,
a high-level JavaScript
API that's actively maintained
to work with any Minecraft
version.
And the beauty of
Mineflayer is it
has access to the game
state's surrounding agent,
like the nearby blocks,
animals, and enemies.
So we effectively have a
ground-truth perception module
as textual input.
And at the same time, Mineflayer
also supports action APIs
that we can compose skills.
And now that we can
convert everything to text,
we are ready to construct
an agent on top of GPT-4.
So on a high level, there
are three components.
One is a coding module
that writes JavaScript code
to control the
game bot, and it's
the main module that generates
the executable actions.
And second, we have a code base
to store the correctly written
code and look it
up in the future
if the agent needs
to recall the skill.
And in this way, we
don't duplicate efforts.
And when we're facing similar
situations in the future,
the agent knows what to do.
And third, we have
a curriculum that
proposes what to do next, given
the agent's current capabilities
and also situation.
And when you wire these
components up together,
you get a loop that drives the
agent indefinitely and achieves
something like
lifelong learning.
So let's zoom in
the center module.
We prompt GPT-4 with
documentations and examples
on how to use a subset
of the Mineflayer API,
and GPT-4 writes code
to take actions given
the current assigned task.
And because JavaScript
runs a code interpreter,
GPT-4 is able to define
functions on the fly
and run it interactively.
But the code that GPT-4 writes
isn't always correct, right?
Just like human errors,
you can't get everything
correct on the first try.
So we developed an iterative
prompting mechanism
to refine the program.
And there are three
types of feedback here.
The environment feedback.
Like, you know, what
are the new materials
you got after taking
an action, or, you
know, some enemies nearby?
And the execution error from
the JavaScript interpreter,
if you wrote some buggy code
like undefined variable,
for example, if it
hallucinates something.
And another GPT-4 that provides
critique through self-reflection
from the Asian state and the
world state, and that also helps
refine the program effectively.
So I want to show
some quick example
of how the critic provides
feedback on the task completion
progress.
So let's say in
the first example,
the task is to craft
a spyglass, and GPT-4
looks at the agent's
inventory and decides
that it has enough copper
but not enough amherst
as a material.
And the second task is to kill
three sheeps to collect food.
And each sheep drops
one unit of wool,
but there are only two
units in the inventory.
So two different reasons and
says that, OK, you have one more
sheep to go, and likewise.
Now, moving on to
the second part.
Once Voyager implements
a skill correctly,
we save it to our
persistent storage.
And you can think of the skill
library as a code repository
written entirely by a language
model through interaction with
the 3D world.
And the agent can
record new skills
and also retrieve skills
from the library facing
similar situations
in the future,
so it doesn't have to go through
this whole program refinement
that we just saw, which
is quite inefficient.
But you do it once,
you save it to disk.
And in this way, Voyager kind of
bootstraps its own capabilities
recursively as it explores
and experiments in a game.
And let's dive a
little bit deeper
into how the skill
library is implemented.
So this is how we
insert a new skill.
First, we use GPT 3.5
to summarize the program
into plain English, and
summarization is very easy.
And GPT-4 is
expensive, so we just
go for a cheaper, cheaper tier.
And then we embed this
summary as the key,
and we save the program,
which is a bunch of code,
as the value.
And we find that doing
this makes retrieval
better because the
summary is more semantic
and the code is a
bit more discreet.
And you insert it.
And now for the
retrieval process.
When Voyager is faced
with a new task,
let's say craft iron
pickaxe, we again
use GPT 3.5 to generate a
hint on how to solve the task,
and that is something like a
natural language paragraph.
And then we embed that
and use that as the query
into the vector database,
and we retrieve the skill
from the library.
So you can think of it as
a kind of in-context replay
buffer in the reinforcement
learning literature.
And now, moving on
to the third part.
We have another GPT-4 that
proposes a task to do,
given its own capabilities
at the moment.
And here, we give GPT-4
a very high-level kind
of unsupervised
objective, that is,
to obtain as many unique
items as possible.
That is our
high-level directive.
And then GPT-4
takes this directive
and implements a curriculum of
progressively harder challenges
and more novel
challenges to solve.
So it's kind of like
curiosity exploration, where
it is called novelty search
in the prior literature
but implemented
purely in context.
Yeah, if you are listening, then
assume the next example is fun.
[LAUGHING]
Let's go through this
example together, right?
Just to show you
how Voyager works,
the whole complicated data
flow that I just showed.
So, the agent finds
itself hungry.
It only has one out
of 20 hunger bar.
So GPT-4 knows that it
needs to find food ASAP.
And then it senses there are
four entities nearby, a cat,
a villager, a pig,
and some wheat seeds.
And now GPT-4 starts a
self-reflection, right?
Like, do I kill the cat and
villager to get some meat?
That sounds horrible.
How about the wheat seeds?
I can use the seeds
to grow a farm,
but that's going to
take a very long time
until I can generate some food.
So, sorry, Piggy.
You are the one being chosen.
[LAUGHTER]
So GPT-4 looks at the inventory,
which is the agent state.
There is a piece of
iron in inventory.
So it recalls--
Voyager recalls a skill
from the library, that
is to craft an iron sword
and then use that skill
to start pursuing, to
start learning a new skill,
and that is hunt pig.
And once the hunt-pig
routine is successful,
GPT-4 saves it to
the skill library.
That's roughly how it works.
Yeah.
And putting all
of these together,
we have this iterative prompting
mechanism, the skill library,
and an automatic curriculum.
And all of these
combine is Voyager's
no-gradient architecture, where
we don't train any new models
or fine-tune any parameters, and
allows Voyager to self-bootstrap
on top of GPT-4
even though we are
treating the underlying
language model as a black box.
It looks like my example worked,
and they started to listen.
[LAUGHS]
Yeah.
So yeah, these are the
tasks that Voyager picked up
along the way.
And we didn't
pre-program any of these.
It's all Voyager's idea.
The agent is kind of
forever curious and also
forever pursuing new
adventures just by itself.
So to quickly show some
quantitative results,
here we have a
learning curve where
the x-axis is the number
of prompting iterations,
and the y-axis is the
number of unique items
that Voyager discovered as
it's exploring in environment.
And these two curves are
baselines, ReAct and Reflection.
And this is AutoGPT, which is
like a popular software repo.
Basically, you can
think of it as combining
ReAct and a task
planner that decomposes
an objective into subgoals.
And this is Voyager.
We're able to obtain
three times more novel
items than the prior methods
and also unlock the entire tech
tree significantly faster.
And if you take away
the scale library,
you see that Voyager
really suffers.
The performance takes a
hit because every time
it needs to kind of
repeat and relearn
every skill from
scratch, and it starts
to make a lot more
mistakes, and that really
degrades the exploration.
Here, these two are the bird-eye
views of the Minecraft map.
And these circles are
what the prior methods
are able to explore given the
same prompting iteration budget.
And we see that they tend
to get stuck in local areas
and kind of fail
to explore more.
But the Voyager is
able to navigate
distances at least two times
as much as the prior works.
So it's able to visit
a lot more places
because to satisfy this
high-level directive
of obtaining as many
unique items as possible,
you've got to travel, right?
If you stay at one
place, you will quickly
exhaust the interesting
things to do.
And Voyager travels
a lot, so that's
how we came up with the name.
So finally, one limitation is
that Voyager does not currently
support visual perception
because the GPT-4 that we
used back then was text only.
But there's nothing
stopping Voyager
from adopting like multimodal
language models in the future.
So here we have a little
proof-of-concept demo
where we ask a human to
basically function as the image
captioner, and the
human will tell Voyager
that as you're building
these houses, what are
the things that are missing?
Like, you place a
door incorrectly.
Like, the roof is also
not done correctly.
So the human is acting as a
critic module of the Voyager
stack.
And we see that with
some of that help,
Voyager is able to build a
farm house and a nether portal,
but it has a hard time
understanding 3D spatial
coordinates just by itself
in a textual domain.
Now, after doing Voyager,
we're considering,
like, where else can we
apply this idea of coding
in an embodied environment,
observe the feedback,
and iteratively
refine the program?
So we came to realize that
physics simulations themselves
are also just Python code.
So why not apply some of
the principles from Voyager
and do something
in another domain?
What if you apply Voyager in a
space of this physics simulator
API?
And this is Eureka, which
my team announced just
like three days ago.
Fresh out of the oven.
It is an open-ended
agent that designs
reward functions for robot
dexterity at superhuman level.
And it turns out that GPT-4
plus reinforcement learning
can spin a pen much
better than I do.
I gave up on this task a long
time ago, from childhood.
It's so hard for me.
So Eureka's idea is very
simple and intuitive.
GPT-4 generates a bunch of
possible reward function
candidates
implemented in Python,
and then you just do a
full reinforcement learning
training loop for each candidate
in a GPU accelerator simulator.
And you get a
performance metric,
and you take the best candidates
and feedback to GPT-4,
and it samples the next
proposals of the candidates
and keeps improving the whole
population of the reward
functions.
That's the whole idea.
It's kind of like an
in-context evolutionary search.
So here's the initial
reward generation,
where Eureka takes as context
the environment code of NVIDIA's
Isaac Sim, and a
task description,
and samples the initial reward
function implementation.
So we found that the simulator
called itself is actually
a very good reference manual
because it tells Eureka what
are the variables you can use.
Like, you know,
the hand positions.
Like, here, the fingertip
position, the fingertip save,
the rotation angular
velocity, et cetera.
So, you know all
of these variables
from the simulator
code, and you know how
they interact with each other.
So that serves as a very
good in-context instruction.
So Eureka doesn't
need to reference
any human-written
reward functions.
And then, once you have
the generated reward,
you plug it into any
reinforcement learning algorithm
and just train it to completion.
So this step is typically
very costly and very slow
because reinforcement
learning itself is slow.
And we were only able to scale
up Eureka because of [INAUDIBLE]
which runs 1,000 simulated
environment copies on a single
GPU.
So basically, you can think
of it as speeding up reality
by 1,000x.
And then, after training, you
will get the performance metrics
back on each reward component.
And as we saw from
Voyager, GPT-4
is very good at self-reflection.
So we leverage that capability.
And there's a software
trial reminding
you to activate a license.
Yeah.
So Voyager reflects on it
and then proposes mutations
on the code.
So here, the mutations we
found can be very diverse,
ranging from something as
simple as just changing
a hyperparameter in the reward
function waiting all the way
to adding completely novel
components to the reward
function.
And in our experiments,
Eureka turns out
to be a superhuman reward
engineer, actually outperforming
some of the
functions implemented
by the expert human engineers
on NVIDIA's Isaac Sim team.
So here are some
more demos of how
Eureka is able to write
very complex rewards that
lead to these extremely
dexterous behaviors.
And we can actually train the
robot hand to rotate pens.
Not just, you know,
in one direction,
but in different directions
along different pseudo-axis.
I think one major
contribution of Eureka,
different from
Voyager, is to bridge
the gap between high-level
reasoning and low-level motor
controls.
So Eureka introduces
a new paradigm
that I'm calling hybrid
gradient architecture.
So recall, Voyager is a
no-gradient architecture.
We don't touch anything,
and we don't train anything.
But Eureka is a hybrid gradient
where a black box inference-only
language model instructs a white
box learnable neural network.
So you can think
of it as two loops.
Right?
The outer loop is
greater than 3,
and it's driven by GPT-4 kind of
selecting the reward functions.
And the inner loop
is gradient-based.
You train it like a full
reinforcement learning episode
from it to achieve
extreme dexterity
using a specialized like--
by training a special
neural network controller.
And you must have both
loops to succeed to deliver
this kind of dexterity.
And I think it will be a very
useful paradigm for training
robot agents in the future.
So, you know, these days,
when I go on Twitter, or X,
I see AI conquering
new lands every week--
you know, chat, image
generation, and music.
They're all very
well within reach.
But MineDojo,
Voyager, and Eureka,
these are just scratching the
surface of open-ended generalist
agents.
And looking forward, I want
to share two key research
directions that I personally
find extremely promising,
and I'm also working
on it myself.
The first is a
continuation of MineCLIP,
basically, how to develop
methods that learn
from internet-scale videos.
And the second is multimodal
foundation models now
that GPT-4V is coming, but it
is just the beginning of an era.
And I think it's important
to have all the modalities
in a single foundation model.
So first, about videos.
We all know that videos
are abundant, right?
Like, so many data on
YouTube, way too many
for our limited GPUs to process.
They're extremely
useful to train
models that not only have
dynamic perception and intuitive
physics but also capture the
complexity of human creativity
and human behaviors.
It's all good, except that
when you are using video
to pre-train embodied
agents, there
is huge distribution shift.
You also don't get
the action labels,
and you don't get
any of the groundings
because you're a
passive observer.
So I think here
is a demonstration
of why learning from
video is hard, even
for natural intelligence.
So little cat is seeing
boxers shaking their head
and it thinks maybe shaking head
is the best way to do fighting.
[LAUGHING]
Right?
This is why learning
from video is hard.
[LAUGHING]
You have no idea, like, why--
[LAUGHS]
This is too good.
Let's play this again.
You have no idea why Tyson
is doing this, right?
Like the cat has no idea.
And then it associates this with
just the wrong kind of policy.
[LAUGHING]
But for sure, you know, it
doesn't help the fighting,
but it definitely boosts
the cat's confidence.
[LAUGHING]
That's why learning
from video is hard.
Now, I want to point out
a few of latest research
in how to leverage so much
video for generalist agents.
There are a couple
of approaches.
The first is the simplest.
Just learn kind of
a visual feature
extractor from the videos.
So this is R3M from
Chelsea's group at Stanford.
And this model is still an
image-level representation,
just that it uses
a video-level loss
function to train
more specifically
time-contrastive learning.
And after that, you can use
this as an image backbone
for any agent,
but you still need
to fine-tune using
domain-specific data
for the agent.
The second path is to learn
reward functions from video,
and MineCLIP is one model
under this category.
It uses a contrastive objective
between the transcript
and video.
And here, this work,
VIP, is another way
to learn a
similarity-based reward
for goal-conditioned
tasks in the image space.
So this work, VIP, is led
by [AUDIO OUT],, who was also
the first author of Eureka, and
Eureka is his internship project
with me.
And the third idea
is very interesting.
Can we directly do imitation
learning from video,
but better than the
cat that we just saw?
So we just said,
you know, the videos
don't have the actions, right?
We need to find some ways
to pseudo-label the actions.
And this is video pre-training
of GPT from OpenAI
last year to solve long-range
tasks in Minecraft.
And here, the pipeline
works like this.
Basically, you use a keyboard
and a mouse, action space.
So you can align this action
space with the human actions.
And OpenAI hires a bunch
of Minecraft players
and actually collect
data in-house.
So they record the episodes
done by those gamers.
And now you have a data set of
video and action pairs, right?
And you train something called
an inverse dynamics model, which
is to take the observation
and then predict
the actions that caused
the observation to change.
So that's the inverse
dynamics model,
and that becomes
a labeler that you
can apply to in-the-wild
YouTube videos that
don't have the actions.
So you apply the IDM to 70K
hours of in-the-wild YouTube
videos, and you will get these
pseudo-actions that are not
always correct but also
way better than random.
And then you train
imitation learning on top
of this augmented data set.
And in this way, OpenAI
is able to greatly expand
the data because the original
data collected from the humans
are high quality, but
they're extremely expensive.
While in-the-wild YouTube
videos are very cheap,
but you don't have the
actions, so they kind of
solved and got the
best of both worlds.
But still, you know, it's really
expensive to hire these humans.
Now, what's beyond
the videos, right?
I'm a firm believer that
multimodal models will be
the future, and I see text as a
very lossy kind of 1D projection
of our physical world.
So it's essential to include
the other sensory modalities
to provide a full,
embodied experience.
And in the context
of embodied agents,
I think the input will be a
mixture of text, images, videos,
and even audio in the future,
and the output will be actions.
So here's a very early example
of a multimodal language
model for robot learning.
So let's imagine
a household robot.
We can ask the robot to bring us
a cup of tea from the kitchen.
But if we want to
be more specific,
I want this particular cup.
That is my favorite cup.
So show me this image.
And we also provide a video demo
of how we want to mop the floor
and ask the robot to imitate
the similar motion in context.
And when the robot sees
an unfamiliar object
like a sweeper, we can explain
it by providing an image
and showing, this is a sweeper.
Now, go ahead and do
something with the tool.
And finally, to
ensure safety, we
can say, take a
picture of that room,
and just do not enter that room.
To achieve this,
back last year, we
proposed a model called VIMA,
which stands for visual motor
attention.
And in this work, we introduced
a concept called multimodal
prompting, where the prompt can
be a mixture of text, image,
and videos.
And this provides a very
expressive API that just unifies
a bunch of different robot tasks
that otherwise would require
a very different pipeline
or specialized models
to solve in prior literature.
And VIMA simply
tokenizes everything,
converting image and text
into sequences of tokens
and training a
transformer on top
to output the robot arm
actions autoregressively
one step at a time
during inference time.
So just to look at some
of the examples here.
Like, this prompt rearrange
objects to match the scene.
It's a classical task
called visual goal
reaching that has a big
body of prior works on it.
And that's how our robot
does it, given this prompt.
And we can also give it
novel concepts in context.
Like, this is a blicket.
This is a wug.
Now, put the wug into a blicket,
and both words are nonsensical.
So it's not in
the training data,
but VIMA is able to generalize
zero-shot and follow the motion
to manipulate this object.
So the bot understands what
we want and then follow
this trajectory.
And finally, we can give
it a more complex prompt.
Like, these are the
safety constraints.
Sweep the box into this, but
without exceeding that line.
And we do this using the
interleaving image and text
tokens.
And recently, Google Brain
Robotics followed up after VIMA
with RT-1 and RT-2, robot
transformer 1 and 2.
And RT-2 is using
a similar recipe
as I described,
where they first kind
of pre-train on
internet-scale data
and then fine-tune with some
human-collected demonstrations
on the Google robots.
And RoboCat from DeepMind
is another interesting work.
They train a single,
unified policy
that works not just
on a single robot
but actually across different
embodiments, different robot
forms, and even generalize
to a new hardware.
So I think this is like a
higher form of multimodal agent
where the physical form factor,
the morphology of the agent
itself, is another modality.
So that concludes our
Looking Forward section.
And lastly, I want to put
all the links together
of the works I described.
So this is minedojo.org.
We have open-source everything.
Well, for all the projects, we
are big fans of open source.
We open source as
much as we can,
including like the model code,
checkpoints, simulator code,
and training data.
And this is
voyager.minedojo.org.
This is Eureka.
And this is VIMA.
And one more thing, right?
If you just want an excuse
to play Minecraft at work,
then MineDojo is perfect
for you because you
are collecting
human demonstration
to train generalist agent.
And if there's one thing that
you take away from this talk,
it should be this slide.
And lastly, I just want
to remind all of us.
You know, despite all
the progress I've shown,
what we can do is still very
far from human ingenuity
as embodied agents.
You know, these are the
videos from our data set
of people doing like
decorating a winter wonderland
or building the functioning
CPU circuit within Minecraft,
and we are very far from
that as AI research.
So here's a call
to the community.
If human can do these
mind-blowing tasks,
then why not our AI, right?
Let's find out together.